Osama Tahboub

Full Stack Developer

41 Linksway, Gatley, SK8 4LA

077 916586965

o.tahboob2000@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://bit.lv/otahboublinkedin

Github:

https://github.com/o-tahboub

Portfolio:

https://o-tahboub.github.io/portfolio

I am a full-stack web developer, with a particular interest in back end technologies.

I have always found it rewarding to help others, and to be involved in local community projects, that is how I started as a volunteer in a local charity, and was later on employed by them.

Through my technical role, I found that software development can be really empowering for an individual or an organisation, and have since trained as a developer.

Skills

I finished a 16 week intensive course on software development in 2018, learning primarily HTML, CSS, PHP, and JavaScript, I have also been introduced to technologies like Bootstrap, SASS, PHP and JavaScript Frameworks.

I am formerly a certified Scrum Master, we used Scrum to manage our projects in Mayden Academy, but I am generally familiar with Scrum principles and have used them on many projects since.

In my roles since, I have worked with a custom CRM based on .NET webforms and Umbraco 7, 8 and 10 websites, along with other technologies, my role was flexible in these projects, I was a developer, technical support, technical advisor and project manager throughout projects to maintain or develop these systems.

Job History

READ Foundation / Systems and Data Developer

Jan 2021 - Present

I am currently working on all READ's digital projects with their partners, this includes an Umbraco website, data migration to a new CRM, data analysis for multiple fundraising platforms.

Human Appeal / Software Developer

Oct 2020 - Dec 2020

I was promoted to Software Developer.

Human Appeal / Junior Software Developer

Jun 2018 - Oct 2021

I returned to Human Appeal as a Junior developer, as the only in house developer I was the first contact for our CRM and website requirements and projects.

Mayden Academy / Trainee

2018 - Present

With aspirations to become a software developer, I applied to Mayden Academy in December 2017, and started with them in February 2018.

Human Appeal / IT Officer

2011 - 2018

After finishing an IT course, and showing that I was keen on a technical role, I started this role with the same employer, and was their support technician for 7 years.

Human Appeal / Logistics Officer

2009 - 2011

My first job after leaving university, I was a volunteer at a local charity, and managed to become an employee once they had a vacancy.

Education

The Open University / TU100 My Digital Life, M250 Object Oriented Programming

2013 - 2015

I wanted to further my technical abilities and get into software development, so I finished a few courses with the Open University on their computing degree, but this proved to be very difficult with little reward, with me having to also work full time at the same time.

MANCAT/ City & Guilds Level 3 IT Diploma, Microsoft Technology Associate (Server Administration, Security and Networking fundamentals)

2010 - 2011

I was already employed at this point, but having aspirations to work in a technical environment, I decided to take a level 3 IT course, which led to me changing roles to my first technical role.